mysurvey.com 2012-06-13

# MySurvey | Discover the Power of Your Opinion

## My Survey Privacy Policy

**Policy Effective Date:** March 1998  
**Last Revised:** December 2011

---|---  
  
This page discloses the privacy practices of the MySurvey.com website. If you arrived at this page via one of our cobranded partner sites, please be assured that the privacy policy that you see here is in effect for all MySurvey.com panel members regardless of how they are directed to our registration form.

(NOTE: We use the term "cobranded" to mean that our partner sites' logo or in some cases, a masthead that looks similar to the partner site appears on the MySurvey.com website pages in order to give the user a sense of continuity. However, only MySurvey.com collects information on MySurvey.com pages; the ways in which we use this information and protect your privacy are described below.)

**Our Privacy Pledge**  
_When you participate as a panel member, your privacy is assured._

  * We will not make any personal information of our panel members available to anyone without your knowledge (as described in this policy), except in the rare instances required by law. This includes your name, address, phone number, and email address.
  * We will never try to sell you anything - that is not our business. We will never sell your name to anyone else who might want to sell you anything.
  * Occasionally, we may contact you to validate responses. We will never misrepresent ourselves or what we are doing.
  *  Your individual responses to surveys will also be kept confidential and will never be linked to your personal identifying information.
  * Your decisions about participating in a study, responding to specific questions, or discontinuing participation will be respected without question.

**How Information Is Used:**  
_The Information We Collect & How We Use It_

When you register as an interactive panel member, we collect the following personal identifying information: your name, postal service address, email address, and phone number.

We use your name and email address to let you know about opportunities to take surveys, to provide new updates about MySurvey.com that may be of interest to our panelists, to enter you automatically into the sweepstakes program, and to inform you about special programs and benefits we are offering to our panel members (such as special gifts or incentives or our sweepstakes program). Generally, panel members are notified about an opportunity to take a survey several times per month. We also send brief emails to our interactive panel members several times a year to provide information of interest and to express our appreciation for their participation.

We use postal service addresses to mail free gifts offered to panel members, prizes to sweepstakes winners, products to test, and cash or merchandise that you redeem with your Reward Points. Products to test, cash prizes and cash redemptions may be mailed directly to panel members by the MySurvey.com team and thus do not require sharing of your name and address with outside parties. However, your name, postal address and email address may also be shared with MySurvey.com reward suppliers when you redeem your Reward Points -so they can ship to you directly. Occasionally, we ask our interactive panel members if they would be willing to take certain special paper and pencil surveys. We ask your permission prior to mailing such surveys as well as providing information about the benefits of taking such a survey. On average, panelists receive something through the U.S. mail once or less per year.

We use phone numbers to notify sweepstakes program winners who have not responded to email. We also call panel members in response to their request for a return call to answer a question or address any concerns. On rare occasions, we call panelists to validate survey responses. Most interactive panel members are never contacted via phone.

MySurvey.com asks sweepstakes prize winners if we can post their first name and last initial (or just their initials) along with home town location on the Winners' page of this website. We post names only after permission is granted and respect any winners' requests that their names not be publicized.

MySurvey.com frequently asks panel members for demographic information (such as age, gender, household composition), computer and web access capabilities, and lifestyle information (for example, types of vehicles owned or business/recreational travel). MySurvey.com uses this information to select surveys that are appropriate for the panel member (or a member of the panelist's household). For example, a survey related to satisfaction with stays at various hotel chains might be sent only to those panelists who indicate a certain frequency of travel. We sometimes use birth date information to send birthday greetings to our panel members.

MySurvey.com asks panel members for their opinions about a variety of products and services by asking them to complete surveys via email or at the MySurvey.com website. Usually, MySurvey.com combines the individual panelist responses and reports on the aggregated (or group) results. Individual level responses are occasionally used, but never associated with any personal identifying information. For surveys offered at the panelist website, panel members are asked for their user name and password (rather than any personal identifying information).

MySurvey.com may occasionally ask for other personal identifying information as part of a specific survey. In these cases, we will provide an explanation in the survey introduction to allow members to make an informed decision about participation. The explanation will include a description of any new identifying information that will be collected via the survey and with whom it will be shared. As with any survey, members can decline to take the survey or stop at any time during the survey process. Like all other information we collect, any additional information collected for a specific survey will be used for research purposes only.

MySurvey.com also automatically collects information via log files to administer the site and to aid in technical problem solving. Log file information collected is IP address, time a page was viewed, name of pages viewed within the MySurvey.com site during the specific visit, browser type, URL parameters, and cookies that were set by the MySurvey.com website at the time of the visit. Log files may also include information indicating where a visitor came from. This information is used only to administer the site and to identify and resolve any technical problems related to the site's operation. Log file information is never linked to personal identifying information.

When you participate in the Refer A Friend program we ask for your friend's first name and email address. The first name is used in the greeting to personalize the message and the email address is needed to deliver it to your friend. Both pieces of information are stored only temporarily, for a long enough time to make sure the email was sent without difficulty and are never used for any other purpose. Participation in the Referral Program, like all aspects of MySurvey.com membership, is completely voluntary.

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. Panel member names, addresses, and phone numbers are maintained on a secured database accessible only by Lightspeed Research, Kantar or MySurvey.com research staff. Panel members may also access their own information for the purposes of verifying and updating, but they cannot view other members' information. As with any Internet endeavor, absolute security of information transmitted through channels (communication networks, hardware, software) not directly operated or controlled by us cannot be guaranteed.

In the event WPP or its affiliates including Kantar and Lightspeed Research experience a merger, acquisition, sale or other transaction pursuant to which this website is acquired by a third party or an affiliate of WPP, your personal information may be disclosed to the third party or affiliate both before and after the transaction, for the sole purpose of facilitating and effecting that transaction. In the event a transaction is consummated, you will be notified of the transaction via email and/or through a notice on our website, and custody of your personal information will be transferred subject to all the terms and restrictions in this privacy policy. In the event the transaction is not consummated, WPP or Kantar will require the third party or affiliate not to use or disclose your personal information in any manner whatsoever and to completely erase the same.

As is the case with any information you provide to any business operating in the United States, information provided to MySurvey.com is subject to disclosure pursuant to judicial or other government subpoenas, warrants, or orders.

**Updating Your Personal Information:**  
_Policies on Correcting/Updating Personal Information_

MySurvey.com relies on panel members themselves to provide any updates to personal identifying information. Members may update email addresses, password, mailing address, phone number as well as name of the person who initially registered by going to the Update Your Info section of this website (available to members only). For changes to any other personal information, including user name, panel members are asked to contact MySurvey.com via email or by phone. The toll-free customer service number is 1-800-537-4097. Customer service hours are 9 AM to 10 PM (Eastern Time) on weekdays and 10 AM to 6 PM on Saturday. Members may also update their email addresses or other information by emailing, by calling, or by mailing in their changes (see postal address at the end of this page), whatever they prefer. (Please note that changes sent via the postal service will take longer to implement due to time needed for mail delivery.) We will respond to your change request within 30 days of receiving it; the response will either be to change your information as requested or to respond to you with more information. (Note: when emailing us with changes to your information, please use the email links provided above.)

MySurvey.com may occasionally supplement information obtained from panel members with third party information (such as demographic or ownership information that MySurvey.com doesn't typically collect, e.g. small dog ownership). In order to accomplish this, we may need to share your information with a third party. MySurvey.com may also use third party database applications to provide services (such as customer support or email communications to members). In such cases, we ensure your privacy by having these third parties sign a written, legally binding agreement stipulating that they will not share MySurvey.com data with any outside party and that any individual identifying information is to be used solely for the purpose of matching records or providing the agreed upon database service.

MySurvey.com may also exchange information with our partner sites for the member's benefit and with the member's knowledge (in accordance with this privacy policy). These benefits include opportunities to earn additional rewards on the partner site and/or to eliminate MySurvey.com advertising to those who are already MySurvey.com members. The information exchanged will be the member ID and/or email address (the minimum information needed to provide the benefit). We ensure your privacy by having our partner sites sign a written, legally binding agreement stipulating they will not share your individual identifying information and that it is to be used solely for the purpose of providing you with additional rewards and to eliminate redundant advertising.

**Opt Out Policy:**  
_Your Decision Not To Participate_

Panel members may decline to respond to a survey or opt to drop interactive panel membership at any time. We respect the decision to decline participation and will not try to dissuade you. Panelists who prefer not to complete a given survey need not do so.

Panelists who would like to withdraw their membership from the interactive panel may do so at any time by contacting MySurvey.com via email or by calling the toll-free customer service number (1-800-537-4097). Customer service hours are 9 AM to 10 PM (Eastern Time) on weekdays and 10 AM to 6 PM on Saturday. Panelists may also withdraw membership by clicking on the unsubscribe link found at the bottom of the My Profile page in the member area of the MySurvey.com site and on the bottom of every email that members receive from MySurvey.com. We will process all unsubscribe requests within 10 days of receipt and usually within 48 hours of receipt.

Upon receipt of the drop request, MySurvey.com may ask you to complete brief survey about the reason(s) for discontinuing membership. This survey is optional and does not involve any additional email; any results will help us improve panel members' experience. Thereafter, MySurvey.com will stop sending survey notifications. However, the panel member will continue to be entered in the sweepstakes drawing for the contest period in which participation was suspended unless the panelist requests otherwise. Following the sweepstakes drawing and any relevant winner notification, no further contact will occur.

**Use of Cookies:**  
_How We Use Cookies & Other Technologies on Our Website_

MySurvey.com uses cookies on our registration and survey forms during the time you are actively completing the forms. These cookies (which may be flash-based cookies or local shared objects) are used solely for technical purposes to allow for accurate transmission of survey information to the MySurvey.com database and to ensure that a member does not take the same survey more than once. For longer surveys, we use cookies to make form completion more convenient for the panelist. They allow for completion of the form in more than one sitting; you take up where you left off rather than starting from the beginning again.

MySurvey.com also uses cookies on the member area of the site to store user name automatically and password (optionally) so that the user does not have to repeatedly retype the information. For users' convenience, this cookie is stored for subsequent sessions. Member area cookies are also used to identify valid members in order to protect access to their specific member information (such as rewards account information) and to personalize their experience on the site. The web server also creates cookies to uniquely identify each user session when a member visits the site. This latter cookie is automatically deleted at the end of a session.

MySurvey.com also uses cookies, including Flash cookies, for advertising research purposes by keeping track of some of the types of online advertisements that you see on the websites that you visit, as well as the number of times that you see those ads.

No personal identifying information is stored on any cookie nor do we retain any cookied information on our databases.

Because cookies are used to identify valid members to protect access to their specific member information and to personalize their member experience, users who choose not to allow cookies cannot register nor can they access the member area of the MySurvey.com website with its associated member benefits (such as taking surveys, earning reward points and redeeming rewards). Members may choose, however, not to receive the cookies that we use for advertising research purposes by contacting MySurvey.com via email, postal mail or by toll-free telephone as described below in the How To Reach Us section of this policy.

Occasionally, we employ technology to provide security of images displayed in our surveys. A script embedded in certain pages displaying images overwrites information located on your computer's clipboard when you are on that page. The script is used very infrequently and only for certain images that are presented. Please be assured that any information you may have copied to your clipboard is not captured or read; rather, it overwritten with blank data. We advise you to paste any information that you have cut or copied to your clipboard before you log in to take a survey.

**Notification Of Changes:**  
_How We Notify You About Changes to Our Privacy Policy_

If we are going to use your personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated in our privacy policy at the time of collection, we will notify you via email. You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in this different manner; instructions for how to make that choice will be included in the email. If we make any material changes to our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our website notifying our members that there is a change and pointing them to the revised privacy page.

Occasionally, we conduct studies with partner companies on the partner's website, which may operate under a different privacy policy. Like all our other studies, participation in these studies is completely voluntary and informed. We notify select members via email about these research opportunities and provide a complete description of what is involved and any member benefits. On occasion, we invite members to take this type of survey without email notification (that is, the survey is waiting when they visit the site or they are invited to take a second survey at the conclusion of participation of another survey). In all these cases, we will explicitly state if some or all of the survey will be conducted at the partner site and if so, what privacy policy is in operation for the study (this MySurvey.com privacy policy or a different policy). As necessary, we will provide a link to the partner's privacy policy or to the policy pertaining to the particular study. This information will be put in the email notification for those surveys that have an email notification. For surveys where there is no email notification, the information will be included in the survey introduction. Members may decline to participate in these studies or drop out of the study at any time. When survey notification is via email, they can simply not click on the link to the survey. If the information is contained in the survey introduction, an easy way will be provided for the user to exit the survey (for example, a button on the survey intro page with "prefer not to participate"; a click exits them from the survey and places them on the last page they visited).

**How To Reach Us:**  
_How to Contact Us About Your Privacy Concerns_

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to the MySurvey.com site coordinator.

  * via email - Click here to email us.
  * via regular mail directed to:

MySurvey.com Technical Support  
2700 Oregon Road  
Northwood, OH 43619

  * by calling our toll free number at 1-800-537-4097 (the phone is staffed from 9 AM to 10 PM (Eastern Time) on weekdays and 10 AM to 6 PM on Saturday)

If the site coordinator has not responded to your inquiry within 7 days or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, contact TRUSTe. To return to the MySurvey.com Website after visiting [TRUSTe](http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php), please use the "Back" button on your browser. 

**Member of TRUSTe:**  
_MySurvey.com is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program_

We also participate in the EU Safe Harbor Privacy Framework as set forth by the United States Department of Commerce. As part of our participation in the Safe Harbor program, we have agreed to TRUSTe dispute resolution for disputes relating to our compliance with the Safe Harbor Privacy Framework. If you have any complaints regarding our compliance with the Safe Harbor you should first contact us. If contacting us does not resolve your complaint, you may raise your complaint with TRUSTe by Internet at <http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php>.
